Guide to the Charles Dewey Hilles Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1885-1955; Series I; (139 boxes)
  - Family correspondence
    - Hilles, Sarah Bell Whitney, 1885-1909 (Box 136, Folder 1894-1909)
    - Hilles, Sarah Bell Whitney, 1909-1911 (Box 137, Folder 1910-1917)
    - Hilles, Sarah Bell Whitney, 1912-1941, undated (Box 138, Folder 1918-1929)
    - Hilles, T. Allen, 1911-1912 (Box 138, Folder 1930)
    - Hilles, William F., 1911-1912 (Box 138, Folder 1930)
    - Hilles, William N., 1898-1911 (Box 138, Folder 1931-1932)
    - Hilles, William T., 1908-1911 (Box 138, Folder 1933)
    - Lee, John Harvey, 1901-1906 (Box 138, Folder 1934)
    - Lee Thomas H., 1907 (Box 138, Folder 1934)
    - MacCracken, Bessie Whiley, 1913-1944 (Box 138, Folder 1935)
    - Miller, Mary Coale Hilles, 1903-1906 (Box 138, Folder 1935)
    - Moore, Emma Lee, 1896-1912 (Box 139, Folder 1936)
    - Moore, Leta, 1903-1909 (Box 139, Folder 1936)
    - Reynolds, Elizabeth L.H., 1899-1957 (Box 139, Folder 1937-1939)
    - Votaw, Eli Hugh Hilles, 1893-1894 (Box 139, Folder 1940)
    - Votaw, Eldon M., 1909 (Box 139, Folder 1940)
    - Whiley, Annie Dill, 1894-1923 (Box 139, Folder 1941)
    - Whiley, Charles B., 1897-1912 (Box 139, Folder 1942)
    - Whiley, F.C., 1892-1911 (Box 139, Folder 1943-1944)
    - Whiley, Fred, 1898-1913 (Box 139, Folder 1945)
    - Whiley, George E., 1896-1908 (Box 139, Folder 1945)
    - Whiley, Harriet, undated (Box 139, Folder 1945)
    - Whiley, Helen, 1909-1911 (Box 139, Folder 1946)
    - Whiley, Mary Moulton, 1899-1902 (Box 139, Folder 1946)
    - Whiley, Olive Pearl, 1906-1909 (Box 139, Folder 1946)
    - Whiley, Sally Wiseman, 1900-1913 (Box 139, Folder 1946)
    - Whiley, Thomas, 1860 (Box 139, Folder 1946)
    - Warthington, M.B., 1900 (Box 139, Folder 1947)
    - Family history and genealogy, Hilles and Whiley families (Box 139, Folder 1948)
    - Financial records of the estate of Samuel and Elizabeth Lee Hilles (Box 139, Folder 1949-1950)
    - Records pertaining to CDH and BWH Vol. XIV Lame Ducks, 5 November 1912 - 4 March 1913 (Box 139, Folder 1951-1952)
- Topical Files, 1885-1950; Series II; (19 boxes)
  This series contains files arranged alphabetically by topic and/or record type.
  - Business Papers
    - Bills and receipts, 1900-1923 (Box 140, Folder 1953)
    - Board meetings, 1933-1948 (Box 140, Folder 1954)
    - Checks, 1921-1930 (Box 140, Folder 1955)
    - Legal agreement and power of attorney, 1922, 1943 (Box 140, Folder 1956)
    - Pamphlets, 1937-1938 (Box 140, Folder 1957)
    - Periodicals, 1936-1950 (Box 140, Folder 1958)
    - Reports, 1921-1948, undated (Box 140, Folder 1959)
    - Reports of others, 1933-1949 (Box 140, Folder 1960-1961)
    - Stock Lists, 1937 (Box 140, Folder 1962)
  - Commentary, 1923-1945, undated (Box 140, Folder 1963-1965)
  - Memorabilia
    - Appointment books, 1913, 1933-1939 (Box 141, Folder 1966-1969)
    - Cards, 1892-1937 (Box 141, Folder 1970)
    - Certificates, 1899-1947 (Box 141, Folder 1971)
    - Engagement calendars, 1906-1911 (Box 142, Folder 1972-1974)
    - Guest book, 1918 (Box 142, Folder 1975)
    - Household account book, 1913-1918 (Box 142, Folder 1976)
    - Invitations, 1909-1911 (Box 142, Folder 1977-1980)
    - Invitations, 1912-1949, undated (Box 143, Folder 1981-1985)
    - Notebook of guest lists and menus, 1911 (Box 143, Folder 1986)
    - Poems, scripts and cartoons, undated (Box 143, Folder 1987)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 143, Folder 1988)
    - Programs
      - Theater, 1903-1913 (Box 143, Folder 1989-1990)
      - Miscellanea, undated (Box 143, Folder 1991)
      - Miscellanea, undated (Box 144, Folder 1992)
    - Wedding materials, 1886 September 30 (Box 144, Folder 1993)
    - Miscellanea, undated (Box 144, Folder 1994)
  - Memoranda, 1915-1939 (Box 145, Folder 1995-2009)
  - Miscellanea, 1940-1949, undated (Box 146, Folder 2010-2013)
  - Photographs
    General
    See also box 160.
    - Family and friends, Undated (Box 147, Folder 2014-2015)
    - Negatives, 1912 (Box 147, Folder 2016)
    - Portraits of Hilles, Undated (Box 147, Folder 2017)
    - Taft's visit to Panama, 1912 (Box 147, Folder 2018)
    - Miscellanea, 1908-1949 (Box 147, Folder 2019-2020)
  - Reform School Work
    - Boys' industrial school, 1898-1901 (Box 148, Folder 2021)
    - N.Y.J.A. Reports, 1900-1918 (Box 148, Folder 2022-2029)
    - Miscellanea (Box 148, Folder 2030)
  - Republican Party Materials
    - Campaign, 1912
      - Death of Vice President James Sherman (Box 149, Folder 2031)
      - Financial lists (Box 149, Folder 2032)
      - Roosevelt materials (Box 149, Folder 2033)
      - Taft badges and buttons (Box 149, Folder 2034)
        The buttons were reported missing in 2009.
      - Taft materials (Box 149, Folder 2035)
      - Textbook proofs (Box 149, Folder 2036)
      - Wilson materials (Box 149, Folder 2037)
    - Campaign Issues, 1912
      - Conservation (Box 149, Folder 2038)
      - Negroes (Box 149A, Folder 2039)
      - Reciprocity (Box 149A, Folder 2040)
      - Tariff (Box 149A, Folder 2041)
      - Trusts (Box 149A, Folder 2042)
    - Lists of prominent Republicans (Box 149A, Folder 2043-2046)
    - Miscellanea, 1908-1916 (Box 149A, Folder 2047-2049)
    - Miscellanea, 1920-1948 (Box 150, Folder 2050-2051)
    - National Committee Proceedings
      - 1912 June 11 - June 12 (Box 150, Folder 2052-2057)
      - 1912 June 12 - June 15 (Box 151, Folder 2058-2065)
      - 1912 June 15 (Box 152, Folder 2066-2068)
    - National Convention, 1912
      - Contested Delegates (Box 152, Folder 2069-2075)
      - Contested Delegates (Box 153, Folder 2076-2079)
      - Tickets (Box 153, Folder 2080)
      - Platform (Box 153, Folder 2081)
      - Primaries (Box 153, Folder 2082-2083)
      - Primary and election laws (Box 153, Folder 2084)
      - State and district conventions (Box 153, Folder 2085)
      - Taft, William H.
        - Speeches, 1907-1912 (Box 153, Folder 2086)
        - Trip
          - Confidential notes, 1911 September - November (Box 153, Folder 2087)
          - Mementos, 1911 September - November (Box 154, Folder 2088)
      - Vorys, Albert I: speeches, 1909-1912 (Box 154, Folder 2089)
  - Speeches and writings, 1885-1935 (Box 154, Folder 2090-2100)
  - Speeches and writings,, n.d., 1935-1949 (Box 155, Folder 2101-2106)
  - Statements of others, 1909-1949 (Box 156, Folder 2107-2109)
  - U.S. Treasury Department
    - Annual Secretary's report, 1909 (Box 157, Folder 2110)
    - Assistant Secretary's reports, 1909-1911 (Box 157, Folder 2111)
    - Health Bureau material, 1910 (Box 157, Folder 2112-2113)
    - Memoranda, undated (Box 157, Folder 2114-2116)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1910 March - October (Box 158, Folder 2117-2118)
    - Report to the President, 1907 (Box 158, Folder 2119)
  - Young, Arthur: Economic Recommendations, 1910 (Box 158, Folder 2120)
- Oversize Materials
  - Handwritten notebook in Latin, undated (Box 159)
  - Kelly, Robert [diplomas (8)], 1823-1825 (Box 159)
  - American Baptist Missionary Union [certificates of membership], 1846 (Box 159)
  - Congress Hotel, Chicago [floor plan], 1911 (Box 159)
  - Texas [map], 1912 (Box 159)
  - Blueprints of heating plant, 1913 (Box 159)
  - Virginia legislature [charts], 1912 (Box 159)
  - Political cartoon, 1912 (Box 159)
  - President Taft appointment of Hilles as secretary to the President [2 copies], 1911 (Box 159)
  - President Taft appointment of Hilles as Assistant Secretary of the Treasury, 1909 (Box 159)
  - State of New York appointment of Hilles as state representative, 1921 (Box 159)
  - Photographs of Hilles, individuals, families, and houses, 1908-1921, undated (Box 160)
  - Sketch of Taft, 1912 (Box 160)